Curriculum Vitae

Daniel Joseph Gomez

1231 SW 3rd Avenue Gainesville, FL 362702 209.407.8614 – danielgomez@ufl.edu

Objective

My career interests are in the applications cellular biology of fending off emerging pathogens, solving diseases with molecular, biophysical, and biotechnical techniques. I will gain the ins and outs of the Omics through academia research. I can present data (present/poster) as it critical to the research process. My works include MDs, PhDs fellows, and graduate students, this gave me the insight to the work ethic necessary for a career in medicinal chemistry. Technical writing has always pleased me because I was able to tell intricate biological stories. I would like to describe molecular mechanisms, create molecular inventions, and include the macromolecules that have elegant structures and functional catalyst that point to relevant detections (infections, diseases, disorders, etc), biomarkers, and extract the pathological implications. After obtaining my BS degree, I will be applying for doctoral candidacy.

Education

Bachelor of Science. University of Florida. Gainesville, FL Department of Microbiology and Cell Science, UF/IFAS-CALS Microbiology and Cell Science

Anticipated 2018-21

John A. Burns School of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University
Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology
Relevant Graduate Coursework

2012-2013

- Intro to the Neurosciences
- Translational Research in NeuroAIDS and Mental Health (TR-NAMH)

Professional Experience

Scientific Ambassador. UF. Gainesville, FL

Dec 2018 - Present

- Raise awareness of Agricultural and Life Science
- The Microbiome
- General Virology
- Molecular Biology
- Biochemistry

Research and Development Coordinator. dosist. San Francisco, CA

Dec 2015-Feb 2016

- CRO selection and negotiation
- Support chief officers and develop market strategies

Research Technician. John A. Burns School of Medicine (JABSOM), Honolulu, HI. Aug 2012-Dec 2013 Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology

- Developing a drug delivery system for HIV-1 Disease in the BBB.
- FACS, Mouse handling, qPCR, NanoDrop
- Autoclave, Vortex, Centrifuge, cell-culture

Research Associate. JABSOM Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology.

Honolulu, HI Jan 2012 - June 2013

- Developing an immunohistochemistry (IHC) system for JCPyV and HIV-1 Disease.
- PI- Dr. Shiramizu, Dr. Nerurkar (~32hrs/week).

Biology Assistant. JABSOM Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology. Honolulu, HI

2012-13

- Develop blood-brain barrier for permeability assays
- Flow Cytometry (FACS)
- qPCR

Research Experience

Undergraduate Research Associate. University of Florida. Gainesville, FL.

2020-2021

- Wong Lab
- Triplett (The Microbiome)

Research and Development Coordinator. dosist. San Francisco, CA

Dec 2015-Feb 2016

- Developing disposable bioengineered micro dosed vape pens as deliverables for market.
- Research Human trials (~40hrs/week).
- Dosist pens (relief, bliss, clam, sleep, passion, arousal)

Research Assistant. UCSD School of Medicine Division of Neuroanesthesia.

Jan 2014-Jun 2014

La Jolla, CA

- Developing a drug delivery system for Neurocardiological Disease protection.
- Caveolin scaffolding life support for heart organ
- PI- Dr. Patel (~5-15hrs/week).

Research Associate. JABSOM Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology.

Honolulu, HI Jan 2014-Jun 2014

- Developing an immunohistochemistry system for JCPyV and HIV-1 Disease.
- Immunocytochemistry procedures in kidney and brain
- PI- Dr. Nerurkar (~40hrs/week).

Research Associate. John A. Burns School of Medicine (JABSOM), Honolulu, HI.

Aug 2012-July 2013

- Developing a drug delivery system for HIV-1 Disease in the BBB.
- PI- Dr. Shiramizu (40hrs/week).

Research Interests

Chemical Biology	Molecular Biology	Neuro-oncology
Immunology	Translational Research	Neuroscience
Drug metabolism	Computational Biology	Emerging Pathogens

Lab skills

Cell culture (Microbial)	DNA synthesis	PCR/qPCR
Mouse handling	Flow cytometry (in vitro)	R

BioinformaticsMicroscopyNGS SequencingGel ElectrophoresisPythonWestern blotsDrug encapsulationDNA/RNA extractionToxicity assays

Excellent computer and analytical skills using a large variety of programs and software, excellent public presentation skills

Publications

Anticipated 2020

Awards and Honors

2020 DiVERGE Program. Scripps Research. Jupiter, FL

Jan 2020

- Science identity and the culture of science
- Crafting applications, Research Writing, Constructing a compelling self-introduction
- Internships and Ongoing research
- The history and background of Scripps Research

Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program (UROP) Award

2013

• \$5000 award.

Teaching Experience

Tutor, 10	Ohrs/week	2012

Organic Chemistry Tutor

University Tutor. 15hrs/week 2011

• CHEM161 General Chemistry (Dr. Hemscheidt)

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant. 20hrs/week 2011

- CHEM161 General Chemistry (Dr. Talisman)
- CHEM161L General Chemistry Lab I (Dr. Talisman)

Medical and Clinical Experience

Volunteer (Shadowing)

2012

• Observed Dr. Slavin, pediatrics and clinical geneticist, in the Medical Genetics section, City of Hope (9 hours/month)

Research Assistant. Hawaii Center for AIDS. Honolulu, HI

2012

2014

John A. Burns School of Medicine

- Conduct clinical and translational research. Blood in canonical, Human patient collection, DNA isolation

Certifications

IRB Training

March 2019

Life Sciences Responsible Conduct of Research Course (RCR)

March 2019

Medical School Pathology - Certificate of Achievement

June 2018

DNA Research with Biopython

Nov 2017

Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp with R

Oct 2017

Google's Go (golang) Programming Language

Oct 2017

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning

Sep 2017

Community Service

Market Research. Berkeley Humane

Animal Welfare	
Community Wellness Advocate. American Cancer Society • Social Services	2014
International Experience	
Violinist. Orchestra	Summer 2006
• France, Belgium	
Teacher. English Language	Summer 2005
Thailand, Laos	
Technical Skills	

Computer proficiency (MS office, Stats, SAS, R), 7 years of lab and research experience, technical writing, strong organizational and leadership skills, project management, Organizational leadership

Professional Organization Membership

American Society for Microbiology	2020
The American Society for Cell Biology (ASCB)	2019
The Journal of Experimental Biology Transforming the Future through Science Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology	2014
The Journal of Immunology (AAI) AAI Centennial A Century of Excellence: Celebrating 100 Years of The Journal of Immunology The American Association of Immunologists, Inc.	2013

Hobbies

Designing, Drafting, Drawing, Stagecraft, Lighting and Sound, Violin Music, Travelling, Photography, Cooking, Health and Fitness